<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: general | Anthony Wijnen]]></title>
  <link href="http://awijnen.github.com/blog/categories/general/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://awijnen.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-02T09:31:03-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://awijnen.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Anthony Wijnen]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[anthony.wijnen@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Programming used to be my kryptonite]]></title>
    <link href="http://awijnen.github.com/blog/2013/02/12/programming-used-to-be-my-kryptonite/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-12T11:43:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://awijnen.github.com/blog/2013/02/12/programming-used-to-be-my-kryptonite</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='container'>
<p>As an EE major I enjoyed dabbling with hardware. Nice and tangible. However, for some strange reason, I consistently cringed at the thought of writing a line of code. </p>

<p>The fact that the first programming class I ever took was an introduction to JAVA might have something to do with that. Thanks a lot <a href="http://www.kul.com">Alma Mater</a>! You managed to disinterest me in the one field that is thoroughly shaking up every traditional industry in the world. Code became my kryptonite. Yet I look ridiculous in spandex, I would die if I jumped out of a window, and I don't have a twelve pack. Not fair!</p>

<img src="http://www.allmotivated.com/pictures/Demotivational-pictures-red_Kryptonite.jpg" alt="Red Kryptonite">
<br><br>

<p>Luckily, I found the light.</p>

<p>Last year, with the advent of some amazing initiatives like <a href="http://www.teamtreehouse.com">Team Treehouse</a>, <a href="www.codeschool.com">CodeSchool</a>, and <a href="www.codecademy.com">Codecademy</a>, we took leaps and bounds with respect to teaching programming. Early 2012, together with <a href="http://www.codecademy.com/blog/50-make-2013-your-code-year">450,000 others</a>, I pledged to add a new skill to my repertoire. To add some fuel to the fire, I took a four-month sabbatical to start off 2013 to attend the <a href="http://www.flatironschool.com">Flatiron School</a>.</p>

<p>I feel strongly about the need to achieve code literacy. Here are four reasons why I think you should too:</p>
<strong>1. Economic value</strong>
<p>Every industry is being disrupted by software. Amazon punched Borders in the face so hard <a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/business/moneybox/2011/07/readers_without_borders.html">they stayed down</a>. iTunes, Spotify, and Pandora are reducing record labels to ‘dumb’ content farms. These are just two examples where software is engulfing large parts of an industry’s value chain.  It’s happening in every industry. Old- and new-skool. Marc Andreessen described it best: <a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424053111903480904576512250915629460.html">‘Software is eating the world’</a>.</p>

<strong>2. Freedom</strong>
<p>Do you know what it takes to write a web or mobile application? A computer. That’s it. Yes, you probably need an outlet to charge it too. But that’s really it. You can code at home, from your local Starbucks, the office, on a plane, or while sitting on your grandma’s couch. Now that’s what I call freedom. Compare that to the cost and effort of setting up any traditional brick-and-mortar business.</p>

<strong>3. Community</strong>
<p>There are plenty of <a href="http://www.hanselman.com/blog/BeyondElvisEinsteinAndMortNewProgrammingStereotypesForWeb20.aspx">stereotypes</a> floating around describing your average programmer. Like any stereotype, they all hold some truth. That being said, I think comradery and a sense of community are what define programmers the most. They are literally always available to help. Just browse over to <a href="http://www.stackoverflow.com">Stack Overflow</a> if you don’t believe me. There’s even a free <a href="http://rails.pockethotline.com/">Rails Hotline</a> for crying out loud.</p>

<strong>4. Creativity</strong>
<p>Finally, coding is an art. It’s a form of expression. Just like writing, composing, or painting. You are presented with a blank slate, and anything is possible from that point on. I strongly feel creativity behaves like muscle does. Flexing them regularly makes you stronger, faster, leaner. Programming will sharpen your mind. Apply it however way you want.</p>


<strong>Conclusion</strong>
<p>Code literacy is at an abysmally low level today. Why? Children and adolescents are not properly stimulated to pick up programming from a young age. It’s a shame, since software is eating the world, taking over large parts of the value chain in nearly every industry.</p>

<p>We don’t need more bankers, consultants, brokers, or any other type of information-shuffler for that matter. We need people that can build. My advice? Learn how to code. Now!</p>

<p>Would you agree?</p>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello World]]></title>
    <link href="http://awijnen.github.com/blog/2013/02/05/hello-world/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-05T20:13:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://awijnen.github.com/blog/2013/02/05/hello-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some text</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
